Delwath: Kenzo, uh, did a-
DM: Kenzo meditated
Delwath: ... meditated with a monk. Wellby, uh, used-
DM: Wellby abused his rogue abilities
Delwath: ... used
DM: Seeker abused his bard abilities
Delwath: Right
Kenzo: As our Arca- Arcana, and now we're...
Delwath: Now we're, now we're engaged with-
DM: Now you're dealing with the-
Delwath: ... most human-like monks who are acting out their various things and, and Delwath, um,
Delwath: uh, pretending to be a student even though he knows everything, and...
Unknown: Damn.
DM: And left is a-
Delwath: Although Delwath actually knows the least of anybody in the party-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... by a significant margin.
DM: Yeah. [laughs] left is a monk that is, um,
DM: uh-
Unknown: Yeah, so Ken-
Delwath: There's a sparring monk and a-
DM: A sparring monk, a praying monk, and a,
DM: and a student monk
Kenzo: So Kenzo goes to the praying monk and sits down in front
Unknown: of him.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh,
DM: what's, what's your...
DM: You're, you're just praying?
DM: Are you, like, what ability are you using or what skill?
Unknown: Well, uh, insight. Insight.
DM: Insight? Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Go ahead.
DM: So you're trying to just kind of get into the scene with this monk to understand-
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, what's, what's, what's, what's the monk praying about?
DM: Well, you can't tell. It's, it's, like, not...
DM: These are incomplete-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... I mean, to complete the story
Kenzo: ... but, like, what's... to the extent that I can understand.
Unknown: Can I get a-
Delwath: Isn't it a monk of Bhishma? Aren't they all monks of Bhishma?
DM: They're monks of Bhishma, so.
Unknown: Yes, perfect.
Delwath: Are you an initiate of Bhishma?
Kenzo: Yeah. Then, then is it a young monk?
DM: No, these are... Every single one of these were the...
DM: Remember they were all the masters.
Unknown: Yeah. Got it. Got it, got it, got it.
Unknown: Oh, cool, okay.
DM: But you're, like, a master.
Delwath: Yeah, exactly.
Kenzo: Yeah. So, so, so Kenzo will do some advanced, uh, you know, some advanced Bhishma praying.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Like, he'll sit and, uh, he'll, he'll, he'll do the, the, you know...
DM: I, I... Yeah, okay.
DM: So insight is good for this.
DM: Roll insight.
Unknown: 15.
Unknown: Uh-oh.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Rogue inspiration
Delwath: Sh- shouldn't Kenzo get advantage because he's a monk of Bhishma?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Bhishma?
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: That makes sense. [laughs]
DM: Okay.
Delwath: I don't think, I don't think Kenzo should fail.
DM: Fine, fine, fine. Yes, you get advantage.
Unknown: 17?
DM: Eh.
Unknown: Damn it.
DM: [laughs] What skill, what skill are you using?
Unknown: Insight.
Kenzo: My insight's only... How do you guys have, like, plus 17 and shit?
Unknown: My insight's-
Delwath: Their ch- I only... My max is plus 11.
Kenzo: Mine's plus 10. I guess my stealth, it's plus 11.
DM: No, your insight's pretty good.
Delwath: Yes.
DM: It's just, it's just, um,
DM: all of these crazy people who have plus 17s-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... because of their expertise and things.
Unknown: Yeah,
Unknown: yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: 17 is, like, so close.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: I think it should just work 'cause it doesn't seem right that Kenzo failed.
Wellby: What about, uh, uh, inspiration?
DM: Just grab, uh, Bardic. Yeah.
DM: You'll definitely succeed with the Bardic.
Delwath: Bardic inspiration, yeah.
Kenzo: The two D12s, pick higher?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right. Nine, so, uh-
DM: Okay. Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... 26.
DM: Yeah. I mean,
DM: my predetermined minimum DC was 18, so.
Unknown: Okay. That's good.
DM: Um, range is 18 to 25-
Delwath: [[Get some warrior, we gotta get that some warrior]]
DM: ... depending on...
DM: Um,
DM: so,
DM: um,
DM: you sit down and you begin to pray, and you're, you're sort of, um,
DM: you know, going through some of the forms, like, like when you commune with nature and stuff.
Unknown: Exactly, yeah. Yeah
DM: ... like, the sort of, um, you know, opening your mind.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And the first thing you notice is you begin to feel the sort of thoughts and the mind of this monk next to you.
DM: Um, and it begins to solidify and sort of drift towards you.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And you sense it also kind of doing the same thing, and your communes with nature is, like, locked together.
Unknown: Yeah. What I do is, like, as I...
Kenzo: 'Cause, you know, there's, there's probably some, like, you know, chant or a thing, you know?
Kenzo: And then, like, if I s- if I sort of sen- I, I try to lock him into my, uh...
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So the monk then climbs out and,
DM: um, sits next to you cross-legged in prayer.
Delwath: Are, are all the monks from the previous ones?
Unknown: Do we have, like, a ghostly shift?
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: They're all following you.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: The last one is sparring.
DM: Oh, and teacher.
Unknown: Teacher.
DM: Sorry, student.
Unknown: Student, yes.
Unknown: Um-
DM: Yeah, that's, that... I kind of...
DM: Seeker has to kind of auto-succeed on.
Unknown: Seeker, um, raises-
Delwath: I think everybody should have auto-succeeded except me [laughs]
DM: Right.
Seeker: Ra- raises it... Seeker raises a piece of illusory chalk and turns to a, a vast chalkboard behind him and erases it with his sleeve a little bit, and says, "Welcome,"
Seeker: type, uh, writes, "Welcome to the introductory..."
Seeker: And then he lets go of the chalk and turns.
Unknown: It keeps writing behind him.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs]
Seeker: "Introductory session of our special topics seminar."
Delwath: How to Survive in Limbo.
Unknown: What's that?
Seeker: No, no, it's actually, it just says Special Topics Seminar, uh, and begins to ask the student questions about their personal interests and life journey to, in order to begin to assess, uh, where
Unknown: to begin the lesson.
Delwath: That's good. [laughs]
Seeker: Learning about who they are and what they're interested in learning.
DM: Um,
DM: so the, the student is not quite, um...
DM: They're still insubstantial, but each time, each time they reappear, um, you can see, like, sort of on the scroll where they're sort of taking notes, um, different
DM: sort of, uh, sketches of
DM: historical Dunmari buildings like the, um,
DM: like the, um, palace in Tokra that was, like, clearly an interest in sort of Dunmari history.
Unknown: Hm.
Seeker: And, uh, so I try to sort of dig deeper and figure out which, you know, geographic region of Dunmar and
Unknown: period of history they're interested in.
DM: They're not substantial enough to communicate that yet.
Seeker: Oh, okay. Well, I try to look at their drawings and, and guess.
DM: You recognize them. They're, it's mostly t- it's all pla- it's all buildings you've seen in Tokra.
Unknown: Mm. Uh-
DM: So Tokra history.
Seeker: Mm, and so I begin to lecture on- My knowledge of Tokra
Delwath: But we actually researched a fair bit about the history of Tokra when we were going after the werewolves.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: There was a bunch of notes that Seeker would've known about, like-
Seeker: And then I, I make an interesting digression about my own experiences.
Seeker: Didn't we, did we dig or use a tunnel under Tokra?
DM: Yes.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: Does the monk start, like, yawning and like looks like, "Oh, I know."
DM: No, make a, make a... The monk is interested.
Unknown: Seeker's a pretty good teacher.
DM: Make a history check.
Kenzo: That's another plus seven.
DM: Plus seven.
Kenzo: That's 24.
Unknown: So wait, the minimum DC is 18.
Delwath: Why are you making them take, make checks?
DM: Oh, that's plus 17.
Unknown: Right.
DM: You automatically succeed.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: That's 24. Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: yes, I hadn't done the math.
DM: Uh,
Unknown: the, the student is actually very interested
DM: as you begin to talk about your, like...
DM: You know, you get distracted talking about architecture, and there's a di- digression into the history of various kinds of architecture and dwarven architecture versus
DM: human architecture, and the student becomes more and more solid as you digress further and further from the topic.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Into the underground tunnels and the battle with the werewolves.
DM: Right. And then finally you're just talking about the battle with the werewolves, and it's not history at all, but they're very interested.
Seeker: Oh, this is a crucial sort of turning point historically, maybe in the history of the entire world, which is the, the rise-
DM: Oh, that's true
Unknown: ... the moment of...
Kenzo: The rise of the what?
DM: That was the first time-
Kenzo: The ladder
DM: ... the ladder came.
Kenzo: Oh my.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: It was the werewolves.
Delwath: It turns out it's a special seminar on the history of ladders.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Of the ladder.
Delwath: The ladder. Of course, of course.
Kenzo: The ladder was the one.
DM: And the, the monk solidifies next to seek- Seeker, leaving only
DM: the sparring.
Kenzo: What was it? He, he, he who climbs so you may rise.
Kenzo: So... [laughs]
Seeker: What's the AI generated epithet about the ladder, which was nonsensical?
Kenzo: No, what was it? It was so good.
Kenzo: It was a...
Unknown: It was, it was like the, the-
Kenzo: He has climbed so you may rise.
Delwath: Yeah, he has climbed so you may rise.
Kenzo: He has climbed so you, you, you may rise.
DM: No, but that's the exact opposite of how the ladder system works.
DM: Correct.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: You have climbed, so I may rise.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Right.
Wellby: So Wellby will go over to the person sparring and, um, start to match what they're doing.
Wellby: Like he'll watch for a few beats and then, like, take the, like mirroring the motions that they're making.
Wellby: So like if they're blocking, he'll kick up to attack, uh,
Wellby: and so on. And just almost like dancing with them over and over and over again.
Unknown: Yeah. Make a, make an attack roll.
Unknown: 27.
DM: Okay, so you're-
Seeker: Wait, wait a minute.
Seeker: [laughs] Where did that number come from?
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Where did I...
Unknown: Where did I get you that roll?
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: Did you just make up a number?
Unknown: A little bit.
Wellby: He said it quickly.
Unknown: Did you notice?
DM: No, I didn't notice.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: Here, I rolled for you, 47.
Unknown: Uh, wait, so you're plus?
Unknown: 17, I think.
Unknown: 37.
DM: No.
Unknown: That was a 20.
DM: Not for an attack roll.
Unknown: It's probably plus-
DM: 11 or something.
Delwath: Well, I rolled a 20. You got a 31.
Wellby: Which is great. You literally just made that up.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: And no one is gonna say anything about it.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Wow.
Unknown: It was a good number.
Unknown: It was well.
DM: [coughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: I thought you had rolled before you went to sit down on the couch.
Unknown: That's true.
Unknown: Maybe.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um, in any case-
Unknown: I thought that for a second.
Unknown: I was like, "No." [laughs]
Kenzo: No, you didn't.
DM: You match the monk and begin sparring with it.
DM: And
DM: with the,
DM: all of the monks here that are,
DM: uh, pantomiming, you crash through the last barrier
DM: with a retinue of monks who solidify into people as you cross into an open monastery,
DM: uh, with a,
DM: uh...
DM: So it's like the cl- it's like the, a cloister, so there's, there's a,
DM: an open courtyard, pretty big, a couple hundred feet across with this building in the center of it, a small dome building in the center of it.
DM: The...
DM: And then the, the cloisters have sort of, uh, a shaded extent that comes over and you can see that there's monks.
DM: It's sandy in the middle,
DM: um, but there's monks that are sweeping.
DM: There's monks that are sort of doing walking circle meditations.
DM: Everything that you see is, like, very repetitive and, um,
DM: sort of strictly choreographed.
DM: Uh, the n- the monks that, um, that are following you sort of stumble out, um, and, and look around, like, briefly awed and then
DM: sort of quickly begin resuming tasks.
DM: And as they, as they carry out these tasks, sweeping, praying, a couple of them are sparring, um, there's, there's some that look like they're, they're making
DM: scrolls or writing something on paper.
DM: Um, there's some that are, uh, you know, what looks like meal prep or something like that.
DM: And as these, these monks that you rescued continue these activities, they start, they become more solid over time as they repeat these choreographed
DM: behaviors. Like when they, when you first pull them through,
DM: they're thin. They're sort of,
DM: uh, desaturated and almost translucent, still sort of misty.
Delwath: Is somebody making hot water?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: And as they begin to repeat these motions over and over, they begin to, like the flesh begins to solidify on them.
Kenzo: It's like Back to the Future when that...
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: None of the monks seem to look like they're particularly interacting with-
Kenzo: Are there, are there, the ones that are like coming back, are they kind of conscious?
Kenzo: Are they like more, are their souls and consciousnesses like more normal?
Kenzo: Or are they just like automatons?
DM: No, no, no. They're, um,
DM: uh...
DM: What it feels like in Soul Sight is, is sort of like there's fuzz that's slowly melting away and revealing-
Delwath: I wonder if they're the ones who like have faded, have like failed at being...
Delwath: The ones who are outside are the ones who like didn't
Delwath: s-
Kenzo: Hmm
Delwath: ... who like Limbo started to take, right?
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. That was the whole implication, that the ones that we first interacted with-
Delwath: Yeah
Kenzo: ... were the most fucked up and destroyed.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: And the closer we are to the monastery, the more-
Delwath: Hmm
Kenzo: ... ordered they are.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: It's, I mean, it, you, you, this is the...
DM: I mean, the idea is that the more they, like, as they continue these kind of-
Delwath: Yes
DM: ... very structured behaviors-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... the kind of limbo fuzz begins-
Delwath: Yeah
DM: ... to melt away.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: It, it would take some time for them, like-
Delwath: Yeah
DM: ... you still sense they're s- they're still kind of fuzzy, right?
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: But they're getting less fuzzy
DM: as they-
Kenzo: Cool
DM: ... carry out these activities.
Kenzo: Excellent.
Delwath: Um, do we see a jade statue?
DM: Well, the jade statue's in the building in the middle.
Delwath: Ah, right. So let's-
Kenzo: Yeah, let's go to the-
Delwath: Shall we?
Kenzo: Let's go
Delwath: ... carefully avoiding the-
Kenzo: I mean, we'll like-
Seeker: ... geometries of the sweeping monks
Delwath: ... st- let the pattern, like be very careful not to disturb the-
DM: Right, not to disturb the pattern.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: We all walk synchronized, in lockstep.
Delwath: Right.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Actually, we should.
Delwath: We shall.
Kenzo: Yep.
Delwath: Like we've never practiced marching before.
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: So as you approach this central building, the door swings open
DM: by itself, and you can see inside, the interior is a nearly perfect copy of, although in smaller scale, of the Temple of the Eight Divines in Drankor.
Kenzo: Whoa.
Delwath: Oh.
DM: Except
DM: that the art has shifted, and it's now stories that, Kenzo, you recognize from...
DM: And actually,
DM: Seeker did like most of the Bhishma initiation, too.
DM: It's like the stories from the-
Delwath: Oh, yeah
DM: ... Bhishma Temple that are now.
Kenzo: You forgot that. Well, you're also... Yeah, that's right.
DM: But Seeker didn't like accept the, you know, will you die and be resurrected thing.
Delwath: Yeah. You did most of the ground up.
DM: Um.
Delwath: Right.
DM: So it's like that, except the stories have been replaced by those stories, by the...
DM: So there's like illuminated illustrations on the ceiling of, you know, Bhishma leading the, um, the Dunmari, of like Bhishma, um, pray, like leading everybody
DM: in prayer, Jeevali being resurrected.
DM: Kind of the story of the, you know, the death and rebirth that was the Festival of Rebirth at the very beginning of the campaign.
Kenzo: Wait, and, uh, in Drankor, this temple was the one sanctuary place that we kept going back to.
Delwath: Right.
DM: Yeah, this was where
DM: Rai had been for-
Kenzo: Yes
DM: ... many years.
Kenzo: Yes, yes, yes.
DM: And in the middle of the
DM: building is a statue of Jade-
Delwath: Oof
DM: ... missing a hand.
Delwath: [laughs] Do you think it's Rai?
DM: The-
Kenzo: Nah.
DM: The, the features look worn, almost eroded, like you can't make out, um,
DM: out details and, but you hear immediately a, a voice in, in your head.
DM: Um,
DM: "Did Dimataur find you, or did he send you?
DM: What brings you here?"
Kenzo: No way.
Kenzo: Wow.
Kenzo: Cool.
Delwath: Yes.
Kenzo: Uh.
Seeker: Yes, we have met Dimataur.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Apollyon's dead.
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo, uh, takes, takes the, the staff with, uh, Rai's hand on it and says, uh, "Uh, um, I think this is yours."
Kenzo: And he,
Unknown: uh, brings the, the hand over.
DM: I think it makes little difference to me now.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: He came all this way.
Unknown: He came all this way to give you a hand.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: And you don't even want it?
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: He'll just go. We'll just go.
Delwath: Fine.
Delwath: [laughs] We struggled for...
Delwath: [laughs]
Wellby: No, no. Why, why a little difference?
DM: Y- you do not...
DM: He seems confused for a moment.
DM: Dimataur did not bring my message?
Kenzo: What was the message?
Delwath: Wait, are we forgetting a message?
DM: No.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Okay. [laughs]
DM: Dimataur might have forgotten a message.
Delwath: [laughs] Dammit, Dimataur.
Wellby: Right. Have you met Dimataur?
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: Di- um, Dimataur's, uh,
Delwath: he's had some adventures.
Wellby: He got old. It's been 30 years.
Delwath: He, um...
DM: He's doing well now.
Delwath: He is doing well. Uh, we left him in charge?
Unknown: In charge of the Circular Island.
Delwath: [laughs] Uh,
DM: n- no, too much to discuss.
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: What was the message
Wellby: that he was to have delivered?
DM: There is...
DM: [sighs] When we tried
DM: some years ago,
DM: a few years only I think, although time passes strangely here-
Kenzo: 30
DM: ... to- Close the portal to Limbo.
DM: I brought a bunch of Dunmari monks into
DM: this place, and I have
DM: done the best I could to
DM: keep them from fading, although, he stops for a minute.
DM: See you have s- brought some back from the edge.
DM: I, I thank you for that.
DM: But
DM: only a fraction of my effort
DM: goes there because
DM: nearby,
DM: nearby as far as
DM: distances in this place are concerned, which
DM: has little actual meaning,
DM: there is a
DM: focus of stability,
DM: a
DM: seed of the material plane or something that has precipitated a,
DM: uh, an island of order of a kind in this place.
DM: And the entity that is
DM: controlling
DM: that seed has been
DM: seeking to drag
DM: Limbo and the material plane closer and closer together,
DM: perhaps intermeshing them entirely.
DM: And I have been trying to stop that, but we are balanced on a knife edge,
DM: and I cannot leave here or the monks will die, and I cannot take them
DM: from this place or...
DM: Well, I've
DM: no idea what might happen
DM: should this
DM: entity succeed in their goal, but
DM: certainly it would not be good for the material plane.
Delwath: Does the entity have the flavor of Cha'mutte?
DM: No.
Kenzo: What do you know of it?
DM: This thing is far, far older than Cha'mutte.
Kenzo: Oh, boy.
Delwath: And I thought Cha'mutte predated time.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, boy.
Unknown: Oh. There is a wound
Unknown: at Isingue.
DM: Yes, I know. That is what I went to close.
DM: I realize now it was not a portal, it was something more complicated.
Seeker: We've come to believe it's a vortex.
DM: Ah.
DM: It makes sense.
DM: Is that why you're here?
Kenzo: Indeed.
Seeker: We've read that the way to heal it is from this side, not the other.
Seeker: That we'll have to draw the Limbo activity away from the wound somehow.
Unknown: With a piece of order.
DM: Well, yes, of course.
DM: That is,
DM: that is what I told Dimataur.
DM: Some powerful Dunmari sorcerer if he could find one.
DM: Although only one of you looks Dunmari.
DM: And he looks at you, and you do not appear to be a sorcerer.
Unknown: I'm not, yeah.
DM: But-
Unknown: He's kind of
DM: ... should not matter so much as long as one of you is...
DM: Well,
DM: it may be a challenge, actually.
DM: I believe that this
DM: fragment of stability is some kind of
DM: hyper dense
DM: series of runes that must be read in precisely the right order, and unfortunately, my eyes no longer work.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Unknown: Well, that's good news.
Kenzo: Yeah, he's good with the runes.
Kenzo: Uh, what do you know of this entity?
Unknown: What more can you tell us?
DM: I believe they are
DM: born of this plane.
DM: Perhaps one of the original inhabitants of this plane.
DM: Somehow
DM: captured and
DM: grown strong by the
DM: influence of this
DM: fragment of the material plane that has seeded a vector of stability.
Unknown: Wait, is it the Orchard Keeper?
DM: No. No.
DM: [laughs]
DM: The Orchard Keeper is something different.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: The, the Orchard Keeper also was, we could have taken the Orchard Keep- I mean, the Orchard Keeper we knew could, right?
Kenzo: Oh, right.
DM: Plus, the Orchard Keeper was not...
DM: Your inference is that the Orchard Keeper was from
DM: somewhere totally alien.
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: right.
DM: Not from Limbo.
Unknown: Not from Limbo.
Kenzo: Right.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: right. So we need to go to this place, take this piece of order, bring it to the rift, use it to-
Kenzo: Pull it back
Unknown: ... pull it back.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: Easy enough.
Kenzo: That sounds-
Delwath: Yeah, like what, what could go wrong?
Unknown: It's only the, you know,
Unknown: original-
Kenzo: Inhabitant
Unknown: ... inhabitant of Limbo
Kenzo: ... of Limbo.
Unknown: So,
Unknown: like, you know.
Kenzo: How do we find this, uh,
Kenzo: this piece of stability and order?
DM: That is not hard. I can guide you easily enough.
Kenzo: And once we're there?
DM: Well, then you'll be on your own.
DM: This is why I told Dimataur I needed help.
DM: One alone can do little when I have two impossible tasks to achieve.
Kenzo: [sighs] Yeah.
Seeker: Okay. What, what are the two tasks?
Kenzo: Keeping the monks alive.
DM: Keeping the monks alive and-
Delwath: Right.
Delwath: Closing the rift
DM: ... closing the rift. Both require my full attention.
Kenzo: Once we-
Unknown: Wait. Sorry, go ahead.
Kenzo: Once we, uh, engage with the entity,
Kenzo: do you have any
Kenzo: guidance or, or advice?
DM: All I can tell you is this:
DM: There are...
DM: I have observed the
DM: nature of life here, such as it is,
DM: and I believe that
DM: this...
DM: Well,
DM: there are things that live in Limbo,
DM: but they are
DM: so unstable and changeable that even as they grow larger and larger and more powerful, they turn
DM: into nothing so much as great weather fronts that travel across the land but have no will or purpose behind them, or rather, it is better
DM: said, their will and purpose changes from moment to moment such that they can never accomplish anything.
DM: And eventually they grow so big that they fragment into tiny
DM: motes of possibility
DM: that grow.
DM: Sometimes you will see what look like beasts moving through the landscape
DM: that are
DM: several of these filaments grown together, and they will eventually merge and grow into bigger and bigger
DM: locuses of chaos.
DM: My belief is that this creature
DM: is what happens when one of these great chaos storms
DM: passes over a locus of stability
DM: and gains a fixed purpose and ability to control its form.
Delwath: So hold on. Did, do we need...
Delwath: The locus of stability itself is what we need, right?
DM: Yes.
Delwath: And that's what the runes are written on, you think?
Delwath: Okay. So we don't actually have to kill the creature.
DM: No.
Delwath: Uh,
Delwath: okay. [laughs]
DM: All right.
Delwath: I mean, we might end up having to kill the creature,
Delwath: but in theory...
Delwath: Hmm.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Kenzo, uh, so th- this, the statue's speaking in our mind, right?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: So it hasn't moved at all even.
DM: Has not moved at all.
Seeker: It is a solid jade.
Kenzo: Kenzo will, uh, approach the statue and he says, um,
Kenzo: uh,
Kenzo: "Rai, I know you don't know me, but, uh, I've carried a piece of your hand with me since I was
Kenzo: a small child. My parents found the piece of you in the deserts,
Kenzo: and we have, over these past many years-"
DM: I have seen you in dreams, yes.
Kenzo: Oh, you have?
Kenzo: That's good to know.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Some of my dreams, I believe.
Kenzo: What's that?
Kenzo: I've seen...
Kenzo: You've seen me in your dreams?
Kenzo: 'Cause I've seen a lot of your dreams.
DM: I've seen you in those dreams, yes.
Kenzo: Wow. Just didn't know that worked that way.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Kenzo: Well, in any case,
Kenzo: it has been
Kenzo: quite a lot of effort as we have, uh,
Kenzo: collected these fragments [staff rattling] and they have been
Kenzo: a big part of how we've been able to get here.
Kenzo: As you can imagine, it's not been, uh, straightforward to find you here in Limbo.
Kenzo: So even if it may not be, uh, as useful as you'd like now, it feels right to give this back to you.
DM: I, I appreciate that.
Kenzo: And, uh, Kenzo, like, kinda Ergy, ergy, ergy, like, unscrews the- [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: ... the, the, the jade hand from, uh, the top of his, uh, staff and then, you know, goes over and, and, uh, you know, respectfully, uh, and humbly
Kenzo: puts the, puts the hand back onto, uh, Rai's stump.
DM: Sort of fuses there.
DM: There's a sort of,
DM: um, brief sort of moment of,
DM: you know,
DM: kind of a relaxed sigh in your mind.
DM: You notice that when you put the hand on, that, like, most of the rest of the statue is actually quite worn.
DM: Like, it's,
DM: you know, it's like a sort of ancient statue that's, like, been eroded in places and it's, like, all the,
DM: all the bits other than the hand is somewhat eroded and, and weathered.
DM: And it's not that noticeable but in contrast to the, like, new hand it's very clear.
DM: And you do get a sense, like a, a sense through your mind like,
DM: you know, this is a nice...
DM: This is nice. Like it's,
DM: you know, the effort of sustaining this for
DM: 30 years even if it hasn't been 30 years here is non-trivial.
DM: And so
DM: there is a, like a,
DM: you know, some relief as you attach the hand.
DM: Like, this helps.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: What preparations can we make to go to this place?
DM: It is...
DM: I mean, it is not far. I have
DM: relied on the
DM: relic of stability myself to keep this place.
Delwath: What, um...
Delwath: Is it fixed in form or are we likely to encounter
Delwath: changes like in the rest of Limbo?
DM: Well, it is
DM: within the domain of
DM: the,
DM: of the order of this
DM: relic.
Delwath: Right.
Delwath: But does the...
Delwath: Sorry, what I'm trying to-
DM: Does not mean that it is not, uh, possible for the entity that rules there to change things at whim.
Delwath: That's what I was trying to get at. Should we anticipate dangers from the entity shifting the ground underneath us?
DM: I would expect great danger, yes, as I am sure they do not wish to
DM: sacrifice this relic
DM: and especially seem interested in
DM: bringing Limbo and the material plane closer.
DM: There have been
DM: moments when things have shifted and I've had to
DM: push back,
DM: and
DM: some of my charges have been lost over time in those moments when my concentration has
DM: foundered slightly.
DM: This is why I,
DM: when I could, asked
DM: for help for I don't know how much longer I can
DM: sustain this.
Kenzo: Tim, would you take a little, a little break?
DM: Yeah. This is, I mean, this is a great time if-
Kenzo: Feel like we got a little discussion going on here and-
DM: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... or, uh, you-
Seeker: That was a great-
Delwath: I was gonna suggest, yeah
Unknown: ... session though because, I mean, I'm just, it was nice to do the recap 'cause it's like it felt like a long session 'cause a lot of things happened.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Which is, there was a great pace and tone
Kenzo: and everything. So it was really neat. Yeah, that was awesome.
Seeker: Ugh. The Limbo mechanic is really cool.
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: Dude, Limbo's the best, man.
DM: Yeah. Should let-
Unknown: That part like I-
DM: ... let them win. Let Limbo leak into the material plane and just, you know, turn everything into-
Kenzo: Dude, I can't, I can't wait for Kenzo to become a, an apprentice to the orchard keeper.
Kenzo: That's gonna be great.
Delwath: He's so stoked for that.
Unknown: That fruit would do really well in the Chardon markets too.
Delwath: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: It's true. We could become like...
Delwath: Well, we'll have the ambassador, then we, we become the merchants, right?
Delwath: Like-
Unknown: Yeah, we'll export.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Well, we can start the halfling trade exporting-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... interdimensional-
Unknown: Oh my God
Delwath: ... fruit
Unknown: ... interdimensional trade.
Kenzo: Yep. Yes. Yep. We sell the, we sell, uh, c- can, we sell chaos fruits.
Seeker: It's all branding, right? Chaos.
Unknown: It's not Limbo. It's not [[Hypria]].
Unknown: It's just magic.
DM: So let's, I mean,
DM: why are we, why don't we take a break for like an hour and a half, some- Do you wanna go, uh, eat some food?
Kenzo: I do, yeah. I do, yeah.
DM: Um-